Gabriel Fairbairn

907 - 8538 River District Crossing Vancouver, BC

gfairbairn1@my.bcit.ca V5S 0C9 (604) 889-5201 linkedin.com/in/gabrielfairbairn github.com/nerdslayer0

Career Highlights

Gabriel's excellent leadership and business communication skills are grounded in 5 years of work experience in professional sales, as well as multiple extra-curricular activities in the programming community. Some major achievements include standardizing the recruitment and organizational processes for the Computer Club leadership committee, hosting mentorship programs, leading several programming workshops for first years, and placing highly at the 2022 invitational SAP Hackathon.

Education

Computer Systems Technology Diploma Term 3 **Database Communications Option**

BCIT, Burnaby BC

Professional Sales Diploma - Marketing Management

Sept 2013-May 2016

Jan 2022-Current

BCIT, Burnaby BC

Technical Skills

Java, Python, JavaScript, Node.js, MySQL, GitHub, React.js, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Firebase, Heroku, Express.is, C

Project Experience

(https://github.com/NerdSlayer0)

Space Warriors Java Game

November 2022-December 2022

Highest contribution in the 3-person term project. A full space-shooter game in Java with a focus on Object Oriented Programming concepts such as abstraction, encapsulation, inheritance, and polymorphism

2022 SAP Invitational Hackathon Submission

November 2022

Placed in Top 10 percentile at invite-only hackathon event hosted by SAP

Built an app over 2 days that promotes employee contact in a work from home environment by connecting users based on activity/break time

GenWe - Generational Vocabulary Game

April 2022-May 2022

BCIT, Burnaby BC

Applied knowledge in server-side DOM, mySQL, HTTPS, socket.io, Heroku web app hosting

Developed an app that promotes understanding between different generational users to provide a positive relationship building

Reportify - COVID-19 Reporting App

January 2022-April 2022

BCIT. Burnaby BC

Applied learning in Javascript, Firebase hosting, Agile Methods, GitHub, HTML5, Bootstrap, and JQuery

Developed a working health reporting app for use in business, sports, and leisure organizations with 2 other teammates

Leadership and Awards

President - BCIT Computer Club

May 2022-Current

BCIT, Burnaby BC

- Re-organized club leadership, organizational, and recruitment processes to guarantee future longevity of the club
- Mentored 4 students over the course of 3 terms
- Hosted mentorship program, recruitment presentations, and various workshops in github tips, midterm success strategies, club orientation, and more

Leadership Member - BCIT Computer Club

January 2022-April 2022

BCIT, Burnaby BC

- Led the term 1 Co-op Informational event and interviewing skills event
- Collaborated with leadership team on organizing BCIT Hackathon and other events

Set Representative - BCIT Computer Systems Technology Class 1A/2A BCIT. Burnaby BC

January 2022-December 2022

- Coordinate quarterly meetings with professors and other set reps in addressing issues amongst students
- Liaison between student body and education staff to promote student success, healthy communication, and dispute handling

TD Bank Entrance Award Recipient

January 2022

BCIT, Burnaby BC

Received the TD Bank Entrance Award for Winter 2022 semester based on grades, leadership efforts, and academic community involvement

Coding for All Club Member

January 2022-Current

BCIT, Burnaby BC

Practiced coding skills in weekly Leetcode sessions

Work Experience

Delivery Driver UpMeals Technologies Inc, Burnaby BC **July 2022-Current**

Account Manager – Financial Service Sales Ritchie Bros. Finance, Burnaby BC June 2019-September 2021

Sales Territory Representative Leavitt Machinery, Langley BC March 2016-April 2019

Activities and Interests

Member of the Metis Nation of BC, Free-diving and jujitsu practitioner, 4.5 level tennis player at local tournaments, advanced skier/snowboarder, gamer, anime/manga consumer